to the last video of the session and we have discussed the study of good binary files which be already present of the intermission called as a law desk and living of land binaries are in this video we will see how the threat actor will use the law beans to do a real real time attack ok.
So, if you see the first up there will be a phishing email so threat actor will send a phishing email with some PPT ok with some PPT documents so they will import the macro documents macro document sorry they will import the macro based malware in the PPT documents so the next step so what the victim will do.
So, the victim will likely they he he he will be opening that email and and he clicked on the weaponized PPT that was a presentation per point presentation click he clicked on that so once he clicked on the PPT malicious macro encoded PPT ok.
So, this is the one. So, the next second the WSC will be already seen the WSC will be basically used to execute the JavaScript files and some visual basics file VBS file. So, after that the rendial will be executing the malicious macro macro program through the process of WSC to.exe ok.
So, after spawning the WSC to .exe then the WSC to respond the PowerShell .exe ok. So, PowerShell using the CINAP publishing server start VBS ok. So, it spawned the PowerShell so when it's once it spawned the PowerShell it downloaded so the PowerShell download the DSC 00 to image from this malicious URL so after the image get downloaded so the next
step step number seven so here we can find so this is not a JPG file ok. So, this this this basically a dealer file the XR download the files and write the file right the file the final dealer to be ok.
So, this image JPG file will be renamed to the dealer ok. So, now it's renamed the dealer called IMAPI2.DL. So, we all know the DL will be executed under the rendial 32.exe so now the rendial 32 executing the DL file which will be malicious here. So, once the DL 32 get executed executed the malicious DL file.
So, it was readarring to readarring to another website and it goes downloading in another JPG file. So, download a DSC 001.GPG from this and finally the 10th so it contains some malicious URL ok.
This image file contains some malicious code the code will be injected so into the explorer.exe ok, assert DL ok.
So, then probably this will be this JPG will be converted to the dealer now the DL will be injected into the explorer.exe ok.
So, this is the complete attack cycle so I will explain one more time. So, now you can first of all you can there is a possible phishing email so user clicked on the phishing email.
So, now the webcast PPT has been opened the PPT triggered the WScript.exe and executed the macro malicious content presented inside the PPT.
Once the WScript executed the WScript spawned the PowerShell.exe because the attacker returns like that it returned the program like that ok.
Now the PowerShell going to one of the externally URL and it was downloading one of the JPG file that was not actually a JPG file. It's a DL file and it was saving just a IMAPator to the DL.
So, we all know the rendial 32 will be have a capability to execute the DL file. So, now the rendial taking the IMAPator 32 sorry IMAPator to the DL and it was started executing.
So, after started executing it was reaching to the another URL called as the KDM is the DLW.AM files. So, it was downloading another JPG.
It will be renamed the JPG into the DL file. So, now the DL file will be injected into the explorer.exe ok.
So, this is the attack cycle. Inter attack cycle for a law desk.
So, this is the same way that the attacker will follow that and they will try to compromise the mission using the a law desk ok.
We will see one more law desk. So, this law desk was related to the bumble demalware. So, this is one of the malware ok.
So, now the phishing mail has been reached to the user. So, once he clicked on the phishing mail it will be redirecting to the one drive and it was downloading the auto downloading the password protected zip file.
So, now the zip file contains two image file ok. The zip file contain the image file ok. So, this is the zip file once the user clicked on the zip file it contains an image ok.
So, that once he now will click on the image file. So, it will be redirecting to another site ok L and K file.
Then K means a shortcut files. Also it contains a PS1 ok, hidden dot PS1 file. So, it was executing it through the PowerShell and there will be a embedded embedded DLL will be there.
So, that will be get loaded ok. So, this is the attack cycle for a bumblebee. So, we will see lot on lot of things in upcoming videos.
So, here they use the PowerShell.exe for a logged in and there are DLL for a log sorry PowerShell for a lot of that and executing DLL from a DLL dedicated to for a lot of that.
And a lot of things for the previous one be seen multiple things ok. This will be a lot of that. PowerShell will be a lot of that.
This explorer will be a lot of that. So, this is the process of all that ok. It will easily, we can easily aware the difference mechanism ok.
Because if you download us some third party application from the, from any of the malware repository or any, any, any, any, any.
So, any excuse from the internet. So, it will be easily get caught by the static detection. So, it will be get detected easily. So, this, this will be by this way will be by pasta and your software and your programs ok.
So, that we are mostly, we are using the log does for attack cycle ok. Yep, we will hop off this video and we will continue our discussion in the next section. See you guys bye bye.